<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://uapmnlcorinthian.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://uapmnlcorinthian.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-07-29T23:34:09+08:00</updated><id>http://uapmnlcorinthian.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">UAP Manila Corinthian Chapter</title><subtitle>Premier community of architectural professionals in Manila. Join events, workshops, and networking opportunities.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Exploring Sustainable Urban Design in Metro Manila</title><link href="http://uapmnlcorinthian.github.io/2025/07/20/sustainable-design-workshop/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exploring Sustainable Urban Design in Metro Manila" /><published>2025-07-20T10:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2025-07-20T10:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://uapmnlcorinthian.github.io/2025/07/20/sustainable-design-workshop</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://uapmnlcorinthian.github.io/2025/07/20/sustainable-design-workshop/"><![CDATA[<p>The rapid pace of urbanization in Metro Manila has presented both opportunities and challenges for architects and planners seeking to integrate sustainability into the city fabric. From green rooftops to permeable pavements, innovative strategies are emerging to enhance resilience, reduce environmental impact, and improve quality of life.</p>

<h2 id="green-infrastructure">Green Infrastructure</h2>

<p>One of the cornerstone strategies is <strong>green infrastructure</strong>, which uses vegetation and natural systems to manage water, improve air quality, and mitigate heat island effects. Examples include:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Vertical gardens</strong> on high-rise facades, reducing cooling loads by up to 20%.</li>
  <li><strong>Bioswales</strong> along major thoroughfares, filtering stormwater runoff before it enters drainage systems.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="adaptive-reuse">Adaptive Reuse</h2>

<p>Faced with limited land, adaptive reuse has become a key approach. Existing warehouses and industrial buildings are being transformed into mixed-use developments, preserving heritage architecture while meeting modern needs. Notable projects:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Silangan Mills</strong>: Converted into a co-working and exhibition space, integrating solar panels and rainwater harvesting.</li>
  <li><strong>Binondo Warehouse Loft</strong>: Retrofitted to include green atriums and natural ventilation, reducing energy consumption.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="community-engagement">Community Engagement</h2>

<p>Sustainable design in the urban context also relies on community participation. Engaging residents through workshops and charrettes ensures designs meet local needs. Recent initiatives:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Barangay Green Teams</strong>: Volunteer groups maintaining community gardens and monitoring tree health.</li>
  <li><strong>Open Streets Manila</strong>: Monthly pedestrianized zones encouraging active transportation and public gathering.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="future-directions">Future Directions</h2>

<p>As Metro Manila evolves, architects are exploring:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Net-zero energy buildings</strong>: Combining solar façades with energy storage solutions.</li>
  <li><strong>Integrated mobility hubs</strong>: Seamlessly connecting public transit, bike share, and pedestrian networks.</li>
</ul>

<p>By embracing these sustainable urban design principles, Metro Manila can build a more resilient, equitable, and vibrant future for all its residents.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An in-depth look at how sustainable design principles are reshaping Metro Manila's urban landscape.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Membership Benefits Released</title><link href="http://uapmnlcorinthian.github.io/2025/07/01/membership-benefits/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Membership Benefits Released" /><published>2025-07-01T09:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2025-07-01T09:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://uapmnlcorinthian.github.io/2025/07/01/membership-benefits</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://uapmnlcorinthian.github.io/2025/07/01/membership-benefits/"><![CDATA[<p>As of <strong>July 1, 2025</strong>, the UAP Manila Corinthian Chapter is proud to unveil a suite of enhanced membership benefits designed to support your professional growth and connect you with the wider architecture community.</p>

<h2 id="1-live-cpd-webinars">1. Live CPD Webinars</h2>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Monthly Expert Sessions</strong>: Join live presentations on sustainable design, advanced BIM techniques, and practice management led by industry leaders.</li>
  <li><strong>On-Demand Access</strong>: All recordings are archived in our secure online portal—watch anytime at your convenience.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="2-exclusive-partner-discounts">2. Exclusive Partner Discounts</h2>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Software Savings</strong>: Enjoy up to 20% off SketchUp Pro and Autodesk subscriptions through our official partnerships.</li>
  <li><strong>Materials &amp; Books</strong>: Receive special member pricing at accredited architecture bookstores and green-building material suppliers.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="3-digital-resource-hub">3. Digital Resource Hub</h2>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Case Studies &amp; Whitepapers</strong>: Gain access to a growing library of project case studies, research papers, and best-practice guides.</li>
  <li><strong>Template Repository</strong>: Download editable templates for project proposals, specifications, and sustainability checklists.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="4-networking--events">4. Networking &amp; Events</h2>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Quarterly Mixers</strong>: Attend our “Design &amp; Dialogue” networking events at top industry venues—expand your professional circle in a casual setting.</li>
  <li><strong>Online Forums</strong>: Engage in moderated discussion boards to share insights, ask questions, and collaborate on emerging challenges.</li>
</ul>

<p>To explore these benefits in detail, log in to your member dashboard or reach out to membership@uapmcc.org for assistance. We look forward to supporting your continued success in the field of architecture!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Explore our new member perks including live CPD webinars, exclusive partner discounts, and access to a digital resource hub.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Annual General Meeting</title><link href="http://uapmnlcorinthian.github.io/2025/06/15/annual-general-meeting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Annual General Meeting" /><published>2025-06-15T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2025-06-15T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://uapmnlcorinthian.github.io/2025/06/15/annual-general-meeting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://uapmnlcorinthian.github.io/2025/06/15/annual-general-meeting/"><![CDATA[<!-- Sample post: _posts/2025-08-15-annual-general-meeting.md -->
<hr />
<p>layout: post
title: “Annual General Meeting Scheduled”
date: 2025-06-15 14:00:00 +0800
banner: “https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1581092331555-c3a2c61a4d8a?auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1200&amp;q=80”
excerpt: “Network, vote, and collaborate at the UAP MCC Annual General Meeting on August 15, 2025.”
—</p>

<p>The UAP Manila Corinthian Chapter is delighted to invite all members to our <strong>Annual General Meeting (AGM)</strong> on <strong>August 15, 2025</strong>, at the historic <strong>UAP MCC Hall</strong>. This year’s AGM promises to be an engaging forum where members can network, contribute to key decisions, and learn about the chapter’s strategic direction for the coming year.</p>

<h3 id="agenda-highlights">Agenda Highlights</h3>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Opening Remarks</strong> (2:00 PM): Our Chapter President will welcome attendees, present a brief overview of achievements from July 2024 to June 2025, and introduce the Board nominees.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Year in Review</strong> (2:15 PM): The Treasurer will deliver the financial report, detailing membership growth, event revenues, and partnership investments. Members will have the opportunity to ask questions and propose budget adjustments.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Board Elections</strong> (3:00 PM): Four positions on the Board of Directors will be elected. Candidate profiles have been circulated via email, and voting will be conducted both in person and electronically for remote attendees.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Strategic Planning Workshop</strong> (3:30 PM): A facilitated breakout session where members will discuss priorities for professional development, community outreach, and sustainability initiatives. Insights gathered will shape our 2025–26 action plan.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Networking &amp; Refreshments</strong> (4:30 PM): Conclude the formal proceedings with light refreshments, allowing members to connect informally with peers, sponsors, and guest speakers.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<h3 id="why-attend">Why Attend?</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Influence Chapter Direction</strong>: Your vote and feedback directly inform strategic decisions, ensuring our programs align with member needs.</li>
  <li><strong>Expand Your Network</strong>: Meet fellow architects, sponsors, and industry partners in a collaborative environment.</li>
  <li><strong>Access Exclusive Insights</strong>: Gain early information on upcoming workshops, competitions, and conferences scheduled for the next year.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="logistics--rsvp">Logistics &amp; RSVP</h3>

<ul>
  <li>
    <table>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>📅 <strong>Date &amp; Time:</strong> Thursday, August 15, 2025</td>
          <td>2:00 PM – 5:00 PM</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
  </li>
  <li>📍 <strong>Venue:</strong> UAP MCC Hall, Ground Floor, United Architects of the Philippines Building, Taft Avenue, Manila</li>
  <li>🖥️ <strong>Virtual Attendance:</strong> A livestream link will be provided upon RSVP for members unable to attend in person.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>RSVP by August 1</strong> to ensure we can accommodate all participants. Please confirm your attendance via the member portal or email events@uapmcc.org. Virtual attendees will receive unique access credentials and voting instructions.</p>

<p>We encourage every member to participate in this cornerstone event of our chapter’s calendar. Together, we will review our accomplishments, elect our leaders, and chart a bold course for the future of architecture in Manila.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[layout: post title: “Annual General Meeting Scheduled” date: 2025-06-15 14:00:00 +0800 banner: “https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1581092331555-c3a2c61a4d8a?auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1200&amp;q=80” excerpt: “Network, vote, and collaborate at the UAP MCC Annual General Meeting on August 15, 2025.” —]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Urban Resilience Initiative</title><link href="http://uapmnlcorinthian.github.io/2025/05/01/urban-resilience-initiative/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Urban Resilience Initiative" /><published>2025-05-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2025-05-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://uapmnlcorinthian.github.io/2025/05/01/urban-resilience-initiative</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://uapmnlcorinthian.github.io/2025/05/01/urban-resilience-initiative/"><![CDATA[<!-- Sample long-form post: _posts/2025-09-01-urban-resilience-initiative.md -->
<hr />
<p>layout: post
title: “Urban Resilience Initiative: Building a Sustainable Future”
date: 2025-05-01 10:00:00 +0800
banner: “https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1562072548-12a8f5c08f0b?auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1200&amp;q=80”
excerpt: “A deep dive into our Urban Resilience Initiative, exploring strategies for sustainable growth, climate adaptation, and community engagement in Metro Manila.”
—</p>

<p>Metro Manila faces growing challenges from rapid urbanization, climate change, and aging infrastructure. To address these issues, the UAP Manila Corinthian Chapter has launched the <strong>Urban Resilience Initiative</strong>, a multi-pronged program designed to foster sustainable growth and strengthen community readiness against environmental risks.</p>

<p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1500322103240-10dffe344e78?auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=800&amp;q=80" alt="City skyline with sustainable green buildings" /></p>

<p>The first component focuses on <strong>green infrastructure</strong>. By integrating vegetated rooftops, permeable pavements, and urban forestry into new and retrofit projects, we aim to reduce heat islands and manage stormwater more effectively. Pilot sites at Pasig Riverfront and Quezon City Memorial Circle have shown a 25% decrease in peak runoff during heavy rains.</p>

<p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1581091013955-5cd7a8d044b1?auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=800&amp;q=80" alt="Workers installing rain garden" /></p>

<p>Next, we emphasize <strong>climate-adaptive design</strong>. Public spaces, schools, and healthcare centers are being redesigned with passive cooling techniques, solar shading, and natural ventilation. Through collaboration with local barangays, demonstration projects in Binangonan and Marikina have improved occupant comfort and reduced energy demands by 15–20%.</p>

<p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1496317899792-9d7dbcd928a1?auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=800&amp;q=80" alt="Architect presenting to community" /></p>

<p>Community engagement remains at the heart of the initiative. We host <strong>workshops and charrettes</strong> that bring together residents, engineers, and policymakers. These sessions yield locally driven solutions—such as recyclable rainwater barrels and neighborhood tree-planting campaigns—empowering citizens to take ownership of resilience measures.</p>

<p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1507120366494-9fa76a0e0992?auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=800&amp;q=80" alt="Community tree planting event" /></p>

<p>On the policy front, our task force advocates for updated <strong>urban planning guidelines</strong>. Proposed amendments include mandatory green space ratios, incentives for adaptive reuse, and stringent floodplain development controls. We’re currently in dialogue with MMDA and city councils to pilot these regulations in targeted districts.</p>

<p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1590908298352-5cdfcd4b2b2f?auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=800&amp;q=80" alt="Meeting with city officials" /></p>

<p>To support ongoing research, the initiative funds <strong>academic partnerships</strong>. University of the Philippines and Ateneo de Manila University conduct assessments on mangrove restoration, coastal erosion, and sustainable transport networks. Findings will be published in our digital resource hub by Q4 2025.</p>

<p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1581091011789-2b7dbecda922?auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=800&amp;q=80" alt="Research lab analysis" /></p>

<p>Finally, the chapter organizes an annual <strong>Resilience Hackathon</strong>, inviting multidisciplinary teams to propose scalable solutions. Last year’s winning concept—a modular flood barrier system—has secured prototype funding from industry sponsors.</p>

<p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1519974719765-e6559eac2575?auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=800&amp;q=80" alt="Hackathon participants collaborating" /></p>

<p>Through the Urban Resilience Initiative, we’re transforming Metro Manila into a model of sustainable, community-driven urbanism. We invite all members to participate in upcoming site visits, policy workshops, and the 2025 Resilience Hackathon on November 20–22. Together, we will build a future that is both vibrant and resilient.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[layout: post title: “Urban Resilience Initiative: Building a Sustainable Future” date: 2025-05-01 10:00:00 +0800 banner: “https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1562072548-12a8f5c08f0b?auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1200&amp;q=80” excerpt: “A deep dive into our Urban Resilience Initiative, exploring strategies for sustainable growth, climate adaptation, and community engagement in Metro Manila.” —]]></summary></entry></feed>